所以假设你想改变一种方法。
So suppose you want to change a method.
你是实施者，你也可以
You're the implementer, and you either
希望更改实现的行为方式，或者
want to change how the implementation behaves or you
希望更改规范本身。
want to change the specification itself.
但你的项目里已经有客户了
But there are already clients out there in your program
或者更进一步取决于方法
or maybe beyond that depend on the method's
现行规范。
current specification.
所以问题是，我们如何比较两个人的行为
So the question is, how do we compare the behaviors of two
规格决定是否可以安全更换
specs to decide whether it's safe to replace
旧规格和新规格
the old spec with the new spec and that it
不会让客户破产吗？
won't break the clients?
有一个定义——一个规范
There's a definition-- a specification
s2大于或等于规范
s2 is stronger than or equal to a specification
s1如果且仅当s2的前提条件是
s1 if and only if s2's precondition is
小于或等于s1和s2的后条件
weaker than or equal to s1's, and s2's postcondition
强于或等于s1，至少对于州
is stronger than or equal to s1's, at least for the states
满足s1的前提条件。
that satisfy s1's precondition.
如果是这样，那么任何实现
If this is the case, then any implementation
满足s2的也可用于满足s1。
that satisfies s2 can also be used to satisfy s1.
替换原规格的s1是安全的
And it's safe to replace the original spec s1
在你的程序中使用这个新的更强大的规范s2。
with this new stronger spec s2 in your program.
所以这两条规则包含了几个想法。
So these two rules embody several ideas.
他们告诉你，你总是可以削弱先决条件。
They tell you you can always weaken the precondition.
您始终可以使用现有的等级库s1，
You can always take an existing spec s1,
使其前提条件变弱，使新的规范s2。
make its precondition weaker, to make a new spec s2.
不会影响客户的
And that won't affect the clients
因为它对客户的要求更少。
because it makes fewer demands on the clients.
较弱的先决条件永远不会让客户不安。
A weaker precondition will never upset a client.
你总是可以加强后处理。
And you can always strengthen the postcondition.
这意味着
That means that the implementation
做出了比原来更多的承诺。
is making more promises than it originally did.
所以那些依赖最初承诺的客户
So the clients that were relying on the original promises
也不会不高兴。
won't be unhappy either.
所以举个例子，记住我们有一个查找的规范--find
So for example, remember we had this spec for find-- find
正好是一个——这是
exactly one-- which is a precondition that the value
你要找的就是一次
you're looking for occurs exactly once
并返回索引。
and returns some index where it occurs.
我们可以用这个更强的规范来代替那个规范
We can replace that spec with this stronger spec, which
先决条件较弱。
has a weaker precondition.
所以不是要求客户
So instead of requiring the client
给我们一个数组，其中的值只出现一次，
to give us an array where the value occurs exactly once,
我们允许这个值不只出现一次，
we allow the value to occur not just exactly once,
但是，事实上，两次，三次，
but, in fact, twice, three times,
你想要多少次就多少次。
as many times as you want.
至少一次是比一次弱的先决条件。
At least once is a weaker precondition than exactly once.
没有一个客户这么说
And none of the clients that call this
会在乎的，因为他们都很满足
will care because they were all satisfying this stronger
先决条件。
precondition before.
所以，当然，他们在做什么
So, of course, what they're doing
将已经满足这一较弱的先决条件。
will already satisfy this weaker precondition.
所以这个规格——把规格改成这个是安全的。
So this spec-- it's safe to change the spec to this.
然后我们可以依次改变规格
We can then in turn change the spec
所以它有更强的后置条件。
so that it has a stronger postcondition.
所以不是说我们可以返回任何索引
So instead of just saying we can return any index i where value
发生，我们将要求实现返回
occurs, we're going to require that the implementation return
值出现的最低索引i。
the lowest index i where the value occurs.
再说一遍，因为我们最初的客户
And again, because our original clients were only
取决于这种脆弱的后条件，
depending on this weak postcondition,
更强的后条件不会影响他们。
the stronger postcondition is not going to bother them.
那么，这个规范呢？
Now, what about this specification?
查找可能丢失，这会削弱后条件
Find can be missing, which weakens the postcondition
到了什么都不是的地步。
to the point where it's nothing.
换句话说，唯一的后置条件--
In other words, the only postcondition--
唯一的前提是
the only precondition really is the types
在这些输入上。
on these inputs that are being put in.
否则，我们不会对
But otherwise, we're not making any requirements on
值是否出现在该数组中。
whether value occurs in that array.
然后因为现在的情况
And then because there are now situations
如果没有索引可以返回，
where there is no index that it can return,
我们必须在后置条件中加上一个条款
we have to add a clause to the postcondition that
如果值不在数组中，则说明它的作用。
says what it does if the value is not in the array.
所以想想这个。
So think about this one.
我们会在练习中回到这里
And we'll come back to it in the exercises
在这一节后面。
that follow this section.
现在，让我们考虑一种视觉方式
Now, let's think about a visual way
考虑规格的强度。
to regard strength of specifications.
所以让我们想象一下这里的空间
So let's imagine that this space here
是所有可能的Java方法的空间。
is the space of all possible Java methods.
这个空间中的每个点代表一个方法
And each point in this space represents a method
实施。
implementation.
所以我们在这里先放了点东西
So we put some points in here for our find first
我们最后的发现。
and our find last.
如果你回头看那段代码，你会首先看到
If you look back at that code, you'll see the find first
最后发现的不是规格。
and find last are not specs.
它们实际上是实现。
They are actually implementations.
它们有实现
They have method bodies that implement
他们的实际行为。
their actual behavior.
所以我们将它们表示为这个空间中的点。
So we're going to denote them as points in this space.
现在，这是一个很大的空间。
Now, this is a big space.
它还包括许多方法的要点，这些方法什么都没有
It also includes points for lots of methods that have nothing
像排序一样在数组中查找
to do with finding in an array like doing sorting
连接字符串。
and concatenating strings.
所以Java中所有可能的方法都在这里。
So all the possible methods in Java are in here.
但这是先找后找的要点。
But these are the points for find first and find last.
现在，在这里，一个规范
Now, in this space, a specification
定义一组点，您可以
defines a set of points, which you
可以认为是一个地区
might think of as a region, where a given
实现可以遵循规范，
implementation can either obey the spec,
能按规格操作
can behave according to the spec satisfying
如果客户遵守了他们的先决条件，
that contract that if the client obeys they precondition,
然后实现遵循后条件。
then the implementation obeys the postcondition.
如果一个实现满足这个规范，
And if an implementation would be-- satisfies that spec,
它会在这个区域内。
it's going to be inside this region.
如果没有，它就会在那个区域之外。
And if it doesn't, it's going to be outside that region.
现在，先找，后找，两者都满意
Now, find first and find last both satisfy
找到一个或多个索引规范
this find one or more any index spec
我们之前在这里看到的——这个就在这里。
that we had earlier up here-- this one right here.
所以我们把它们放在代表
So we would place them inside the circle representing
那个规格。
that spec.
现在，想想客户在做什么
Now, one way to think about what clients are doing
是他们在看这个空间的这个规格。
is that they're looking in on this space at this spec.
他们实际上只能看到这个规格。
And they can actually only really see this spec.
此规范的作用类似于防火墙
This specification acts like a firewall
在这里，客户无法真正看透。
here that clients can't really see through.
一个很好的思考方法
One reason that's a nice way to think about it
意思是在这个边界内，
is that it means that within this boundary,
在这个空间内，实现者有自由
within this space, implementers have the freedom
四处移动，根据需要修改代码，
to move around, changing their code as much as they want,
改变函数的行为，
changing the behavior of that function,
不用担心会让客户不安
without fear of upsetting a client as long
因为他们不在防火墙之外。
as they don't go outside this firewall.
这很重要，因为它可以让实现者改进
This is important because it lets the implementer improve
他们算法的性能，
the performance of their algorithm,
或许可以清理他们代码的清晰性，
maybe clean up the clarity of their code,
当他们发现
change what they're doing when they discover
虫子之类的东西。
a bug, that sort of thing.
所以我们可以在像find first这样的实现之间移动
So we can move between implementations like find first
找到最后一点或其他任何一点
and find last or any of the other points
在这个区域内。
inside this region.
客户不会在意，因为他们只是
And clients won't care because they're just
取决于这个规格。
depending on this spec.
他们取决于整个地区能否履行合同
They're depending on this whole region satisfying the contract
他们所依赖的。
that they're depending on.
客户不知道哪个实现
Clients don't know which implementation
他们会得到的。
they're going to get.
他们必须尊重规格。
They have to respect the spec.
但他们也有改变的自由
But they also have the freedom to change
他们如何毫无畏惧地使用实现
how they're using the implementation without fear
他们会——事情会突然破裂。
that they will-- that things will suddenly break.
所以与其朝这个方向打电话，
So instead of calling in this direction,
我们可以想象他们是朝这个方向来的。
we might imagine their calling in this direction instead.
但只要他们尊重这个边界，
But as long as they're respecting this boundary,
一切都会好起来的。
things are going to work.
现在，类似的规格如何
Now, how do similar specifications
在这张视觉图片中相互关联？
relate to one another in this visual picture?
假设我们从规范s1开始
So suppose we start with a specification s1
并使用它创建新的规范s2。
and use it to create a new specification s2.
假设s2比s1强。
And suppose s2 is stronger than s1.
换言之，用s2代替s1是安全的。
So it's, in other words, safe to replace s1 with s2.
那么这些规格将如何出现在我们的图表中？
Then how will these specs appear in our diagram?
让我们先考虑一下加强
Let's think first about strengthening
后条件。
the postcondition.
s2的后置条件强于s1的后置条件。
s2's postcondition is stronger than s1's postcondition.
我们知道，根据定义，s2是一个更强的规范
And we know that s2 is a stronger spec by the definition
我们已经付出了。
that we already gave.
现在，这对实现者意味着什么
Now, what that means for implementers
是因为他们没有多少自由。
is that they have less freedom.
他们对产量的要求更高。
The requirements on their output is stronger.
也许他们以前满足于找到一个或多个索引
Maybe they previously satisfied find one or more any index
通过返回一些与值匹配的任意索引i。
by returning some arbitrary index i that matches the value.
但现在，规格更严格了。
But now, the spec is tighter.
现在，规范要求他们
Now, the spec is returning that they-- demanding that they
返回最低索引i。
return the lowest index i.
所以现在有一些实现
So there are now implementations that
在这个s1里面，但是在这个s2外面。
are inside this s1 here, but outside this s2.
在find中是否有实现
Could there be implementations inside find
一个或多个第一索引，但在外部查找
one or more first index, but outside find
一个或多个索引？
one or more any index?
不，因为所有这些实现
No, because all of those implementations
满足比找到一个或多个
satisfy a stronger precondition than what find one or more
任何索引要求。
any index demands.
现在，让我们想想会发生什么
Now, let's think about what happens
如果我们削弱后条件，这又使
if we weaken the postcondition, which again makes
s2是一个更强的规格。
s2 a stronger specification.
实现必须处理以前的新输入
Implementations have to handle new inputs that were previously
不包括在规范中。
excluded by the spec.
如果他们以前在这些输入上表现不好，
If they behaved badly on those inputs before,
我们不会注意到的。
we wouldn't have noticed.
但现在，他们的不良行为暴露了出来。
But now, their bad behavior is exposed.
我们看到当s2比s1强时，
We see that when s2 is stronger than s1,
它在这个图中定义了一个较小的区域。
it defines a smaller region in this diagram.
较弱的规范将定义更大的区域。
And a weaker specification would define a larger region.
所以在这个例子中，如果我们
So for this example, if we introduced
这个新规范找到一个或多个第一索引，
this new spec find one or more first index,
首先，这个实现仍然满足它。
find first, that implementation still satisfies it.
所以它在这个新规范的圈子里。
So it's inside the circle of this new spec.
但最后的发现并不能满足它，
But find last doesn't satisfy it,
所以它不在这个范围内。
so it's outside the region of that spec.
我们还可以有另一个规格s3
And we could also have another spec s3
它既不强也不弱于s2。
that is neither stronger nor weaker than s2.
可能会重叠。
It might overlap.
所以可能会有实现
So there might be implementations
只满足s1，s3，或者两者都满足
that satisfy only s1, only s3, or that satisfy both of them
一起。
together.
或者它们可能完全不相交。
Or they might be entirely disjoint.
可能没有办法编写一个实现
There might be no way to write an implementation that
同时满足s1和s3。
satisfies both s1 and s3.